

ArchitectRox2023

Christopher Blackwell Lead Application Security Architect

ChrisyBEE88@gmail.com, 08005624@hope.ac.uk <u>LinkedIn</u>, <u>Credly</u>, <u>Stack Overflow</u>, <u>GitHub</u>, <u>DockerHub</u>

I have over 10 years development experience since graduating from University with a degree in Computer Science back in 2011. I have over 6 years' experience working with iPipeline applications since 2016. I have over 3 years' experience working in a security role. And I have been excelling as a Senior Developer for about 2 years. Over the last few years, I have gained professional certification related to DevSecOps:



CompTIA Network Infrastructure Professional – CNIP Stackable...



CompTIA Server+ Certification



CompTIA Network Vulnerability Assessment Professional – CNV...



CompTIA PenTest+ ce Certification



Ping Identity Certified Professional -PingAccess



Ping Identity Certified Professional -PingFederate



AWS Certified DevOps Engineer – Professional Amazon Web Services Training and Certification



CompTIA Linux Network Professional – CLNP Stackable...



CompTIA Systems Support Specialist – CSSS Stackable Certification



CompTIA Linux+ ce Certification



CompTIA Secure Infrastructure Specialist – CSIS Stackable...



CompTIA IT Operations Specialist - CIOS Stackable...



CompTIA A+ ce Certification



CompTIA Cloud Admin Professional - CCAP Stackable Certification



CompTIA Network+ ce Certification



CompTIA Secure Cloud Professional – CSCP Stackable Certification



CompTIA Cloud+ ce Certification



Professional Scrum Master™ I (PSM I) Scrum.org



CompTIA Security+ ce Certification



AWS Certified Security - Specialty Amazon Web Services Training and Certification



AWS Certified SysOps Administrator – Associate Amazon Web Services Training and Certification



AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate

Associate

Amazon Web Services

Training and Certification



AWS Certified Developer – Associate Amazon Web Services Training and Certification



AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner Amazon Web Services Training and Certification

2008 - 2011

- Advanced Website Development C#, ASP.NET, Web Forms, Silverlight
- Website Development PHP 5, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, LAMP
- Applications Development Java 6, Web Based Java Applets, JSP
- Object Orientated Software Development OOP, SOLID, Clean Code, C++
- Database Technology Relational Databases, Normalisation, SQL, T-SQL, MySQL
- Networks and Operating Systems, Data Communication and Security
- Computer Fundamentals, Exploring Computer Science



FST 1844

Employment History	
<u>iPipeline –</u>	INSURANCE ACCELERATED
Lead Application Security Architect	1/01/2023
Senior Developer (Security Rep)	1/06/2020
UK R&D Security Representative	1/08/2019
Full Stack Developer	24/10/2016
https://www.ipipeline.com/uk	

Ref: Craig Broadman, Director R&D DevOps, cbroadman@ipipeline.com Ref: Rach Parker, Delivery Manager, rparker@ipipeline.com,

03033012

03033012

- SaaS , Service Orientated Architecture, Financial Services (C# Web API 2, WCF SOAP API)
- Water-Scrum-Fall (Waterfall, Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Lean), project phase gates, TFS, Jira
- Angular (SPA), JasmineJS tests, HTML5, SCSS, LESS, JS ES6, Typescript,
- Async C# (TPL, TAP, EAP), ASP.NET 4.7.2, .Net Core, MVC 5, MEF,
- WEB API 2, REST, Swagger-UI, Clean Microservice Architecture, Design Patterns, DDD
- WCF, SOAP 1.2 API, XML, WSDL, XSLT, XHTML, Origo, XML Encryption, X509 Certificates
- OWASP, NIST 800, Checkmarx,, SAST, DAST, SCA, Selenium, Gherkin, Spec Flow
- Git, TFS, Octopus Deploy, MS-SQL, T-SQL, Stored Procedures, MongoDB, MQL, GDPR
- Identity Server, Ping Identity TLS/SSL Oauth2 OIDC JWT Implicit Flow Authorisation Code Flow
- Aws certification, CompTIA certification, MongoDB University, Pluralsight, LinkedIn Learning

River Agency – Mobile Developer (Xamarin, iOS, Android) 2015 – 2016

www.riveragency.com

Ref: Chris Brown, IT Manager, Chris.Brown@riveragency.com,

07737 419 552

- Clarks Our World, ASDA Stars, Compass Promises, Recognition Engagement Surveys
- Mobile App Development, Xamarin Studio, C#, XAML, Xamarin Forms for iOS and Android
- Agile, Scrum, VSO/TFS, Git, CI, Team City, Hockey App, Test Flight, Xamarin Test Cloud, Azure
- Async C#, ASP.NET4.5, MVC5, MVVM, Web API 2, REST,HTML5,CSS3,JS ES6, jQuery,JSON
- EF 6 DB First, Stored Procedures, T-SQL, DB Projects SSDT, ADO.NET, Ling
- Mobile App Security, Encrypted Device Storage, OWASP, API Security, OAuth 2, Implicit Flow

DATASCOPE .Net Developer (MVC) 2014 – 2015

www.datascopesystems.com

Ref: Adrian Butt, Managing Director, adrian.butt@datascopeplc.com

08454 507 387

Ref: Dave Walmsley, Dev Manager, david.walmsley@datascopeplc.com

08454 507 387

- Network Rail Time and Attendance Map, Mobile Muster report, Software as a Service (SaaS)
- HTML5, CSS3, JS ES5, Ajax, JSON, jQuery, jQueryUI, jQueryMobile, Git
- C# 5, MVC5, MVVM, ASP.NET 4.5, Bootstrap 3, Sonar Cube
- EF 5 DB First, T-SQL, Stored Procedures, ADO.NET, Ling To SQL, DPA

21stcd – Full Stack Web Developer

2013 - 2014

Ref: Eddie Payne, Managing Director, eddie@21stcd.com

- HTML5, CSS3, C#, ASP.NET 4, T-SQL, ADO.NET, Stored Proc, JS ES3, jQuery, Server 2012R2
- N-tier Web Applications, Mobile First, Responsive, Adaptive, Websites, SVN Source Control
- www.theatresevern.co.uk, www.oldmarkethall.co.uk, www.stantonburytheatre.co.uk

<u> Approach Us – Junior Developer</u>

2012 – 2013

Ref: Luke Read, Development Manager, luke@approachus.co.uk

Bespoke CMS, HTML5, CSS3, JS, ¡Query, C# ASP.NET 4, T-SQL, Stored Proc, ADO.NET

Tag Business Computing Ltd

2011 – 2012

Backup Software, VStudio2010, C#, SQL, Hypervisors, VM Ware, vSphere, Oracle Virtual Box